[eerie music playing]
[distorted dialogue]
[footsteps running]
[tense music playing]
[panting]
-Can I see?
-[Kirsh] Five previously
undiscovered species collected,
but the crew lost containment.
Look with your eyes.
[screaming]
-[shouting]
-[Curly] Hey! Throw it down!
You okay?
Why couldn't we keep our names?
When they made us.
I don't know,
I think it's 'cause we're a secret.
You know, like, they're all code names.
How come Peter Pan?
Why didn't we get to choose?
I don't know, sweetie. I…
I think just 'cause Lost Boys,
you know, they don't grow up.
But they put us in grown-up bodies.
We're not even all boys, we're half girls.
How come Wendy gets to be Wendy?
Because Wendy was the first.
Nibs is a good name.
You know, in the book,
they called Curly "Pickles."
She's always getting into trouble,
you know? Like, "into a pickle."
Well, at least Curly was in on the action.
Tootles always missed everything
'cause he stepped off round the corner.
[Kirsh] Quiet now.
[ringing through intercom]
Kirsh.
[Boy Cavalier] Assume
I know everything from the feed.
This is no longer a rescue mission.
I want you to secure the site,
collect alien life forms,
and bring them back for study.
Boss, as much as I'd love to--
S-Sir, I think--
[Boy Cavalier]
Enough with the "I know better."
[stammers, chuckles]
A trillion dollars of R and D
just landed in our laps.
She fucked up, Yutani,
so we're supposed to what?
Just say, "All good,"
and give her her bioweapons back?
Sir, we are weeks away from launching
a product that will change the world.
-Boss, these are very dangerous--
-Oh, please, please,
we have a high quarantine lab
in the sublevels.
You said it yourself.
It's five species. We bag them, isolate,
do a full workup.
How are my kids?
I have three of them with me.
They've done well so far.
-[Boy Cavalier] Including Wendy?
-[groans]
-Kirsh?
-No, she went to find her brother.
Oh, so she's just out there on her own.
I sent Slightly with her.
He's a child. I told you to watch her.
Her, specifically.
Sir, with all due respect,
it's a crash site,
and we're trying to contain
an alien invasion.
I thought you were supposed
to be better than a man,
but all I'm hearing are excuses.
Bring her in. Now.
[line clicks]
So Wendy's just out there?
With all these things?
[dramatic music playing]
[sirens wailing]
Joe! [panting]
-J--
-[alien clicking]
Joe. [panting]
-[crashes]
-[alien clicking]
Joe!
[Hermit] No, Marcy!
-It's a trap!
-Joe!
-[Hermit] No!
Joe.
[Hermit] No. No, no, no.
Marcy.
[groans, panting]
-[groans] Jesus.
-I got you.
-Marcy, you've got to get out of here.
-[grunts]
-It's coming back.
[Marcy grunting]
-Marcy.
-[grunts, panting]
-Marcy. Marcy!
-[grunts]
[alien hissing]
[breathing heavily]
[growling]
Well, stay behind me.
-I'm the soldier. You're a kid.
-Not anymore.
Marcy.
[alien clicking]
[hissing]
-Should we--
-No.
[banging on ceiling]
[banging stops]
-[grunts]
-[alien screeching]
Why is it doing that?
It's acid.
-We gotta get out of here.
-[banging on ceiling]
[both grunting, panting]
[alien screeches]
[grunts]
Marcy.
[screeching]
[whispers] Marcy.
Marcy.
-[grunts, screams]
-[alien growls]
[grunts, coughs]
[gasps, shudders]
[growls]
[alien screeching]
-What are you doing?
-I don't know!
Joe, the door!
Get to the door!
[grunts]
[Marcy] Joe!
Ready? [grunts]
-Now!
-[door buzzes]
Marcy!
[buzzer sounds]
Marcy! Marcy!
-[Marcy grunting]
-[alien screeching]
[Marcy grunting, screaming]
-[thuds]
-I'm coming!
[Marcy grunts]
[door buzzing]
-[bell ringing]
-Come on, come on, come on.
-[door buzzing]
-Fuck. Marcy!
[grunting]
Marcy.
No.
No, no, no.
[gags, coughs blood]
[breathing heavily]
Marcy. Marcy. You're gonna be okay.
[stammering]
You're gonna be okay.
Marcy, I'm here, okay?
[breathing heavily]
[groans, choking]
Stay with me. Stay… [breathing heavily]
Wendy?
[ominous music playing]
[squelches]
[glass shatters]
[metal thuds]
[sighs] Bro! [groans]
Finally.
Kirsh wants you, bro.
You scared the shit out of me, bro!
-[Smee] Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
-What's wrong with you?
[Smee] Ah! All right.
[both grunting]
[Smee] Sorry, bro.
It's creepy as fuck out there, bro.
[both breathing heavily]
-You said fuck.
-You said shit.
[both chuckling]
-Bro.
-Yeah?
-Can you believe we're on a spaceship?
-Yeah, underground,
which is a dumb ass place
to put a spaceship if you ask me.
Pfft.
Wait. [stammers]
What are those?
Eggs, I think.
-Ah! Dude. Oh!
-What?
-Dude.
We saw this, like… this, like, space bugs…
-Space bugs?
-…that drink, like, all your blood.
-What?
-Right?
And then we saw
this super messed up, like,
-octopus eye monster.
-Octopus?
Dude, come on.
-I can't believe I missed that.
-Bro. Bro.
It tried to yoke Nibs.
-No. Come…
-It was like…
[grunts, yells]
-Like, bro.
-Aw, dude…
-It was full-on sci-fi.
-That sucks.
-Bro. Wait.
-[groans]
-I should've been there.
-Where's Wendy?
-Dude!
-What?
This 12-foot-tall alien thing,
it just took her brother from there.
And she's gone all
hunter-killer mode now in pursuit.
Wait, alone?
She said stay here. I would have gone.
-Huh.
-Yeah.
What do you think
is in these eggs, like, really?
-Not chickens.
-[chuckles]
-Check this out.
-What? Check this out.
-[person] Turn around.
-I can--
Slowly.
Drop your guns.
[Smee] We don't have any guns.
-[Slightly] Yeah, they don't let us.
-[whispers] Shut up.
-[Slightly] It's okay.
-No, it's not.
Move away from the eggs.
Slowly. Over to me.
Mm-mmm.
Where are we?
What do you mean? A spaceship.
No, where? What city?
It's a Prodigy city. It starts…
It starts with a S.
[both] Um…
-Uh… New Siam.
-New Siam.
-Yeah. Yeah.
-New Siam. I knew it.
What, is this… is this your ship?
Did you crash?
-That must have hurt.
-[Slightly] Did it hurt?
Quiet.
[whispers indistinctly]
-You're like a couple of kids.
-[Slightly groans]
-We are not kids!
-Yeah, no, we're not.
[both] We're not kids.
What are you doing here?
Do you come for the specimen?
Um…
-That's… classified.
-It's classified.
Yeah, it's classified.
All right. Um…
[clicks tongue] Here's a scenario.
You're the chief security officer
on a… on a ship.
A deep space research vessel.
So, this ship finds something
on a faraway moon.
Eggs.
Wait, like, these eggs?
Right. These eggs,
they're not like normal eggs.
And when you take them onto the ship,
they start to hatch.
And monsters come out.
You've met them, I think.
The monsters.
Um…
-I think we should…
-I think… Yeah, um… Sorry, we're…
Okay. Sorry… We're just…
-[whispers] Let's go.
There's a feeling you get in this scenario
when the monsters come and you can't…
[computer beeps]
…you don't help.
[machinery whirring]
[Mother] Commencing data transfer.
Maybe you're feeling it now.
When Mother says
the crew's life don't matter,
only the bounty matters.
When you hear the screams,
and all you can do is save yourself.
Are you a robot?
[chuckles]
Wouldn't that be nice?
To be all machine instead of what I am.
The worst parts of a man.
[Mother] Data transfer at 78%.
So… [breathing heavily]
What…
What would you do?
In the scenario.
Could you harm others
or allow them to be harmed?
Could you follow those orders?
-No, not, like…
-Are they bad people?
Does it matter?
Yeah. I mean, you know,
if it was to protect someone
like… like a friend or--
Like our… Like our parents.
Yeah. Like our parents.
[Mother] Data transfer at 93%.
You don't know.
Is that possible?
Know what?
Well, your bodies are clearly synthetic,
but you think you have parents.
-Oh, no. It's just 'cause we…
-[whispers] No. Don't. Shh.
Don't tell him.
Tell me what?
-Nothing.
-[Mother] Data transfer at 98%.
Ninety-nine.
100.
[pants]
-Data transfer complete.
-[machinery powering down]
Data erased from source.
[interface chimes]
Tell me what?
[grunting]
When is a machine not a machine?
[choking] Get off me.
[Slightly choking]
Let him go.
[Slightly breathing heavily]
Ah! He has a gun.
I can see that.
Hey. You're on my ship.
This ship, to be clear,
is an object, not a location.
It's a ball that got hit over the fence
into the neighbor's yard.
I'm the neighbor,
so the ship belongs to me now.
-You're Prodigy?
-I work for Prodigy.
I don't talk to errand boys.
And which country are you king of again?
Are you the parent?
Excuse me?
These synths,
they think they have parents.
Are you the parent?
We're not here to talk about
what I am, Mr. Morrow.
I read the manifest.
Chief of security. Sole survivor. Cyborg.
Lost a lot of friends, did you?
I don't have friends.
Everybody needs friends.
She won't let you have them.
What's on this ship, she spent billions.
People's lives. They belong to her.
[eggs rumbling]
If you're not careful,
you're gonna belong to them.
[tense music plays]
[alien screeches]
-Dude. Dude.
-No!
[gentle music playing]
[truck beeping]
[machinery humming]
[yelling]
[music continues]
We've swept the crash site.
No sign of the cyborg.
-[radio chatter]
-[clicking lips]
[heart monitor beeping]
[music continues]
[gentle music fades]
[sinister music plays]
[machinery beeping]
-[Dame Sylvia] Is she gonna--
-Just give me a second.
I need a full firmware review.
Loop in the skeletal team.
They'll scan for microfractures.
This is my fault.
It's no one's fault. She made a choice.
She's a child.
I'm her guardian.
He made a choice, not you.
And he's the boss, but…
If you ask me,
sending a… a billion-dollar prototype
-to an active crash site is--
-[Boy Kavalier] What?
Nothing.
-Yeah, nothing.
-[Boy Kavalier] No?
What were you gonna say?
Look, it's your company.
You can decide whatever you wanna do.
Please, grow a spine.
Enough.
What happened happened.
And she was so brave, our girl.
I can't even believe it,
but she took a lot of damage.
So if you could just please
let us get on with our jobs.
-Can you save her?
-Yeah, I'm doing tests right now.
-Can I talk to her?
-No.
No. Kirsh suspended her hardware
at the site.
It seemed the safest option.
I'm looking at her here.
I'm worried about that, okay?
Careful.
Fascinating.
You can go.
Well done, you two.
Was it worth it?
What?
Risking a decade's work
on something new and shiny.
My, you're all so feisty today.
[Boy Kavalier scoffs]
I thought you'd be excited.
All this ground to break.
New life-forms.
With acid for blood. [chuckles]
Like an undiscovered country.
And here you are.
A scientist.
-Out.
-Hey. Hey. Hey.
Out.
-Hey.
-[knocks on door]
What the fuck?
It's a parasite.
The Xenomorph lays its eggs.
They wait for organic life to draw near,
only to hatch some kind of proto-creature.
How do you know that?
I saw it earlier
with the security officer.
The body in the cryotube
was killed from the inside.
The proto-creatures must have gestated
inside a human host.
Like you.
Lock it down.
Nobody in or out who isn't synthetic.
You're in charge.
As you wish.
Psst.
Um… [stammers]
Are we in trouble?
[smacks lips] Why?
Have you done something?
[stammers]
No, sir.
Exactly what we were told.
Tell me about this security officer
that you encountered.
Um…
Well, he had a… he had a knife in his arm.
Yeah, like a… like a robot arm,
and he… he threatened Slightly.
Well, both of us really.
Yeah, but it was my neck.
Yeah, but after he'd done you,
he would've done me as well.
-Well, then he…
-Quiet.
There's no sign of him at the site.
We think he managed
to slip through the cordon.
We're circulating images we took
from your retinal cameras.
Our what?
Your eyes.
We record everything you see.
[chuckles] Like, shut up. Really?
I don't think I like that.
There's one thing I didn't catch though.
What did he whisper to you?
At the end.
Uh…
He said,
"When is a machine not a machine?"
[scoffs]
[scoffs] Fine.
[clicks tongue] That's all for now.
Uh, y-you'll find him though, right?
Like, h-he's not gonna…
Um…
Going to what?
I-I don't know.
Like, come here, kill us in our sleep.
Of course not.
This is a secure facility
in the middle of an ocean.
No.
Trust me.
He'll be dead or in custody
by the day's end.
-[door opens, closes]
-Thank you.
[siren wailing in distance]
[engine whirring]
[people chattering]
[baby crying]
[phone beeping]
-[ringing]
-[sighs]
[person] Weyland-Yutani.
Security code 871. Key word: Falcon.
-[dog barking]
-Hold, please.
Mr. Morrow.
[Morrow] Who is this?
Do you have my specimens?
I need to speak with Yutani.
I have code word clearance.
[Yutani] This is her.
Ah. I see. Yes.
You used to know my grandmother.
It's been 65 years, Mr. Morrow.
I run the enterprise today.
Now,
where are my creatures?
Captured, but I have the data.
The data is good,
but it's not enough.
Did they survive?
Yes. We were sabotaged.
Come in and we'll do a full debrief.
Who is Prodigy?
A rival, run by a child.
I can get them back.
I see a way in.
No. You've done enough. Come home.
I don't have a home.
I'm gone a lifetime.
Everyone I know is dead.
Yes, well,
you should have read your contract.
I'm not complaining.
I'm just telling you.
This…
These creatures, they are my life's work.
And I'm gonna get them back.
[phone chimes]
[announcer] Prodigy is forever.
Prodigy is…
They're running tests on her now.
I assume that's why you're here.
You sent us on a mission.
I'm here to report.
I sent Wendy on a mission.
But she got broken.
So here you are.
She's your favorite.
Says who?
Smart people don't ask dumb questions,
I thought.
She's my favorite
because she was the first.
My dad always threw the first pancake
in the trash.
[scoffs]
Is this where you made us?
Yeah. Does that bother you?
No.
Not everyone would like that, you know.
Being artificial suddenly. [chuckles]
No more blood.
No more heart.
-No more pooping.
-[chuckles]
I'm okay with that
if I get to live forever.
But does it…
Does it… does it bother you?
That Wendy's my favorite?
No.
I just think you're wrong. I'm the best.
[scoffs] Really? Why?
All she cares about is her stupid brother.
But I think about things.
What kind of things?
The world.
How to make it better. I have ideas.
What kind of ideas?
No way. If I tell you, you'll steal them.
True.
I'm saying I think I could be you one day.
More than you maybe.
But she doesn't care about that.
You know,
and you gave us these big brains or the…
this hard drive or whatever.
Memory.
I learned French.
-When?
-Last week.
I asked Arthur to upload all the lessons.
[speaking French]
Do you know what a prodigy is?
Sure. A child genius.
Yeah.
But what most people don't understand
is what makes them geniuses
is the fact that they're children.
Because children have access
to a world of infinite imagination.
Like me.
Like you.
[chuckles] Tell you what.
I'm gonna give you some books to read,
some recordings to listen to,
some things to think about.
And then we can get together
and play.
How's that sound?
Does this mean I'm your favorite now?
No.
But you're in the race.
[water dripping]
[through TV] We'll find each other.
Just follow the slime.
[chattering through TV]
[Morrow] Did you figure it out?
My riddle.
I figured out yours.
Who is that?
[techno music playing]
When is a machine not a machine?
I don't want to talk to you.
I know. I'm sorry if I scared you before.
I hadn't figured it out yet.
You.
Is there any way I can make it up?
[breathing shakily]
Just leave me alone, please.
Please.
[chattering through TV]
[breathing shakily]
[Morrow] Ask me how I figured it out.
[sniffs]
Figured what out?
Your riddle.
How can a synthetic being have parents?
I'm-I'm not supposed to talk about that.
Said the child to the stranger.
I'm not a child.
Well, let me ask you this.
How old are you?
Mmm?
I'm a parent, you know.
A father.
I was. I had a little girl.
She hated raisins.
I have to go.
Of course. Yeah.
-We'll talk tomorrow.
-No!
No. [stammers] I mean, no, I can't.
You know, you said something
very wise to me before.
Do you remember?
"Everybody needs a friend."
Will you be my friend?
Please?
Okay.
Thank you. I feel so much better now.
Sleep tight. Don't let the bed bugs bite.
Hello?
[child Nibs] When do we get to go home?
[Mother] We don't.
[liquid spraying]
[ominous music playing]
[music stops]
[high pitched ringing]
[device chimes]
[ringing stops]
[aliens chirping]
-[heart monitor beeping]
-[oxygen pumping]
[aliens chirping]
[keypad beeping]
[door closes]
[cart humming]
[Kirsh] I've selected an egg
approximately 54 centimeters wide.
It's 77 centimeters tall.
Come in close
on the incision point, please.
T, get the suction tube.
[inhales deeply]
If it tries to escape, vacuum it up.
[aliens chirping]
[saw whirring]
[buzzing]
[alien chirping]
[buzzing continues]
[screeching]
[grunting]
[groans]
[screeching]
[oxygen pumping]
[chirping, buzzing intensifies]
[electricity crackles]
-[alien screeches]
-[groans]
[screeching stops]
[breathing heavily]
-[buzzing]
-[screams]
[grunts, breathes heavily]
[crackles]
[alien chirping]
[breathing heavily]
-[alien screeching]
-[groans]
[thuds]
[breathing]
[suspenseful music plays]
["Wherever I May Roam" playing]
♪ And the road becomes my bride ♪
♪ I have stripped of all but pride ♪
♪ So in her I do confide ♪
♪ And she keeps me satisfied ♪
♪ Gives me all I need ♪
♪ And with dust in throat I crave ♪
♪ Only knowledge will I save ♪
♪ To the game you stay a slave ♪
♪ Rover, wanderer, nomad, vagabond ♪
♪ Call me what you will, yeah ♪
♪ Wherever I may roam ♪
♪ Wherever I may roam, yeah ♪
♪ Wherever I may wander, wander, wander ♪
♪ Wherever I may roam ♪
[song ends]